<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: html | Art Of Programming]]></title>
  <link href="http://ApproachE.com/blog/categories/html/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ApproachE.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-03-06T13:03:25+11:00</updated>
  <id>http://ApproachE.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Dmytrii Nagirniak]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[KnockoutJS Validations Screencast]]></title>
    <link href="http://ApproachE.com/blog/knockoutjs-validations-video/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-22T20:31:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://ApproachE.com/blog/knockoutjs-validations-video</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<div>
If you wonder how you can use KnockoutJS with Rails in a similar way to Backbone.js or Spine.js then <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cJzQl-bpmUI">watch the video</a>. It also shows how easy it is to apply client side validations that work alongsite with the server-side validations.<br />
<br />

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/cJzQl-bpmUI?hd=1" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>

<div>
Have a look at the <a href="https://github.com/dnagir/knockout-rails">knockout-rails</a> project for more details.
</div>

</div></div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Dmytrii Nagirniak</div>
<div class='content'>
This is actually <a href="https://gist.github.com/9ca5dce0524927d69655" rel="nofollow">one of the options</a> of validating in the background: <br /><br />It doesn&#39;t include the bindings, but gives idea how it can be done. Easier than I thought actually.</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Dmytrii Nagirniak</div>
<div class='content'>
Pre-validating on the server can technically be done with the Model Events. But it&#39;s not supported out of the box.<br /><br />It is a good idea, but there&#39;s a bit more complexity involved on both client and server. But I&#39;ll gladly accept pull requests to knockout-rails if somebody needs to support that.</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Aleksey Gureiev</div>
<div class='content'>
This comment has been removed by the author.</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[HTML5 and CSS3: Develop with Tomorrow's Standards Today]]></title>
    <link href="http://ApproachE.com/blog/html5-and-css3-develop-with-tomorrow/"/>
    <updated>2010-07-01T09:31:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://ApproachE.com/blog/html5-and-css3-develop-with-tomorrow</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
If you are not living under the rock, you must know a lot of buzzing around HTML5 and CSS3.<br />
And if you want to keep up with technologies so that you won’t become a grand daddy saying “I work with HTML1 and no CSS which works on all browsers”, then you DO HAVE to learn HTML5.<br />
And there is one more opportunity for that, a great book from the great publisher (PragProg):<br />
<a href="http://pragprog.com/titles/bhh5/html5-and-css3" target="_blank">HTML5 and CSS3: Develop with Tomorrow's Standards Today</a><br />
Looking at the excerpts, I do like it for now and will get it as soon as I will have finished some of my other readings.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[HTML 5 Readiness]]></title>
    <link href="http://ApproachE.com/blog/html-5-readiness/"/>
    <updated>2010-04-20T20:55:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://ApproachE.com/blog/html-5-readiness</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
A friend of mine just sent me the link:&nbsp;<a href="http://html5readiness.com/">HTML 5 Readiness</a>.<br />
Check it out - it shows browsers support for HTML5.<br />
<br />
As always Internet Explorer is far behind. Chrome is doing very, very well.<br />
<br />
And one more link (not really related) for myself as a note: <a href="http://everytimezone.com/">visual time zone representation</a>.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[HTML5 Presentation]]></title>
    <link href="http://ApproachE.com/blog/html5-presentation/"/>
    <updated>2010-04-18T23:30:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://ApproachE.com/blog/html5-presentation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
One of the easiest and best <a href="http://apirocks.com/html5/html5.html">presentations about HTML5</a>.<br />
Just must see thing.<br />
<br />
What I like about it is that it:<br />
<br />
<ul>
<li>is actually a simple HTML5 web site;</li>
<li>describes most notable features of HTML5 AND</li>
<li>allow to see the features in action (provided that you browser supports HTML5).</li>
</ul>
<div>
<br /></div>
<br />
<br /></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Content Management/Publishing System Problems]]></title>
    <link href="http://ApproachE.com/blog/content-managementpublishing-system/"/>
    <updated>2009-10-24T01:20:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://ApproachE.com/blog/content-managementpublishing-system</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
Reading the <a href="http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/archives/001306.html">Treating user Myopia</a> I remembered one thing I has been thinking about lately: the problems of all Content Management Systems.<br />
Please note that I will be talking about Web Content Publishing which produces (as an end result) a web page represented with HTML.<br />
<br />
Since first CMS the bunch of issues started to arise and most of them are related to basic things:<br />
<ol>
<li>How user should edit the content?</li>
<li>How the content provided by user should be represented as HTML?</li>
</ol>
<h4>


Editing user content</h4>
<div>
The most popular options to edit the content are:</div>
<div>
<ol>
<li><b>Poor HTML</b> - user can provide HTML as it is.</li>
<li><b>Plain text</b> - the text is rendered as-as. Similar to 1, but is HTML encoded, so this is really 1-to-1 match of the text.</li>
<li><b>Plain text with formatting</b> - user edits the plain text according to specific rules, then the text is parsed and renders as HTML.</li>
<li><b>Rich Editing (WYSIWYG)</b> - is basically user friendly poor HTML. The main difference is that user should not know the HTML itself (with all its pros and cons).</li>
<li><b>Preprocessed HTML</b> - this is mix of Poor HTML/Rich Editing and Plain text with formatting. The edited content is in format of HTML but reserves special markup to be parsed dynamically. (Think of ASP.NET, JSP or any other dynamic page generated on server, but provided by user)</li>
</ol>
<div>
To give you an idea where each of them is used and its benefits or issues:</div>
<div>
<ol>
<li><b>Poor HTML</b>&nbsp;- usually used in primitive/simple management systems. But is always (&gt;99%) used as a back-door when options 4 is available. Characteristics:</li>
<br />
<ol>
<li>Very customisable (anything that can be represented with HTML can be done in this mode).</li>
<li>Requires knowledge from the users.</li>
<li>The actual output is 100% corresponds to the edited content.</li>
<li>Easily overused (users can apply fonts/colors/text size etc with no actual need).</li>
<li>Previous point leads to non-maintainable CMS itself as it is technically very hard change common layout with this approach.</li>
<li>No way to enforce web-standards.</li>
<li>No way to enforce common site layout rules.</li>
</ol>
<br />
<li><b>Plain text.</b>&nbsp;Is actually part of any system (not only CMS). We can see that everywhere where users' input is shown on a page. It anything from Contact Us and Registration form a real CMS. Its characteristics:</li>
<br />
<ol>
<li>Easy to edit.</li>
<li>No customisation points at all. The output will always be plain text.</li>
<li>The actual output will often be different (newlines and space in plain text are in most cases displayed as such, but just ignored by browsers).</li>
<li>Web-standards are automatically enforced.</li>
<li>Common site layout rules are N/A.</li>
</ol>
<br />
<li><b>Plain text with formatting.</b> Is used in most of Wiki sites. Often called Markdown. The aim is to allow user to edit content in plain text, but reformat it to rich (HTML) content according to the rules of Markdown. Characteristics:</li>
<br />
<ol>
<li>Requires users' knowledge of the markdown.</li>
<li>There are a lot differen mark-ups/downs which increases learning curve for end-users overall.</li>
<li>Really describes the content and NOT how to represent the content.</li>
<li>Has limited customisation. Only set of particular HTML tags can be rendered as a result.</li>
<li>Easy to enforce web-standards.</li>
<li>Easy to enforce common site layout rules.</li>
</ol>
<br />
<li><b>Rich Editing (WYSIWYG).</b>&nbsp;The aim is to provide users ability to edit content and see how it looks just in place. What You See Is What you get. Used in most of CMS systems, blogs, forums etc where there is a requirement to publish something better than just a plain text. Considered to be the must-have option and is a de-facto standard for content publishing these days. Characteristics (some inherited from Poor HTML):</li>
<br />
<ol>
<li>Very customisable.</li>
<li>Does not requires knowledge from the users (easy to use).</li>
<li>The actual output in most cases is &gt; 90% similar to the edited content (which is pretty good).</li>
<li>Easily overused (users can apply fonts/colors/text size etc with no actual need).</li>
<li>Previous point leads to non-maintainable CMS itself as it is technically very hard change common layout with this approach.</li>
<li>Issues with the editors.</li>
<li>No way to enforce web-standards.</li>
<li>No way to enforce common site layout rules.</li>
<li>Copy-paste from other documents is very buggy.</li>
</ol>
<br />
<li><b>Preprocessed HTML/MarkDown</b>&nbsp;- this can used in systems that dynamically build online forms or are in some way application builders. The idea is to allow user to provide a content but still make it dynamic. Usually used in pretty complex applications. Typical example I can take from top of my head is <a href="http://www.mindtouch.com/">DekiWiki</a>. Characteristics:</li>
<br />
<ol>
<li>Requires knowledge of the markup.</li>
<li>Customisation points are limited.</li>
<li>Content is always mixed with dynamic&nbsp;behavior&nbsp;which leads to painful&nbsp;maintainability.</li>
<li>The actual output is often totally different comparing to the original content.</li>
<li>No way to enforce web-standards.</li>
<li>No way to enforce common site layout rules.</li>
</ol>
</ol>
</div>
<div>
Probably, the Rich Editor is the golden middle here. But the things go wrong when people try to copy-paste content (very rich-formatted), let's say, from MS Word. Hardly any WYSIWYG editor can handle that. And the result output will be awful. Forget about web standards....</div>
<div>
<br /></div>
<div>
The point I want to make here is that there is no unique option for all possible solutions. If you create a system for geeks - use mardown, for normal users - use Rich Editor and be prepared to review its content.</div>
<div>
<br /></div>
<div>
But generally, I feel there is a lack of science behind this. We need to analyse this area to provide a good solution for both users and developers, so they can live happy lives and not bother writing posts like the&nbsp;<a href="http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/archives/001306.html">Treating user Myopia</a>.</div>
</div>
<br />
For any ideas on how to solve this publishing issue I promise beer.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
