<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: podcast | Art Of Programming]]></title>
  <link href="http://ApproachE.com/blog/categories/podcast/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ApproachE.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-03-04T23:05:08+11:00</updated>
  <id>http://ApproachE.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Dmytrii Nagirniak]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[.NET Podcasts]]></title>
    <link href="http://ApproachE.com/blog/net-podcasts/"/>
    <updated>2009-05-27T09:37:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://ApproachE.com/blog/net-podcasts</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
Just a list of resources that might be useful for a lot of people:<br />
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.dotnetrocks.com/" target="_blank">.NET Rocks</a> - a weekly talk show for anyone interested in programming on the Microsoft .NET platform.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.hanselminutes.com/" target="_blank">Hanselminutes</a> - a weekly audio talk show with noted web developer and technologist Scott Hanselman and hosted by Carl Franklin. Scott discusses utilities and tools, gives practical how-to advice, and discusses ASP.NET or Windows issues and workarounds.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.altnetpodcast.com/" target="_blank">Alt.NET podcast</a> – number of podcasts on a lot of topics around .NET (BTW, <a href="http://ozalt.net/" target="_blank">here’s Aussie Alt.NET site</a>).</li>
<li><a href="http://herdingcode.com/" target="_blank">Herding Code</a> - a weekly podcast with K. Scott Allen, Kevin Dente, Scott Koon, and Jon Galloway.</li>
<li><a href="http://aspnetpodcast.com/" target="_blank">ASP.Net Podcast</a> - brings a technology focus to the area of podcasts.&nbsp; This podcast is geared towards developers with applications that scale to a large amount of data and users.</li>
<li><a href="http://deepfriedbytes.com/" target="_blank">Deep Fried Bytes</a> - an audio talk show with a Southern flavor hosted by technologists and developers <a href="http://keithelder.net/blog/">Keith Elder</a> and <a href="http://blog.cloudsocket.com/">Chris Woodruff</a>. The show discusses a wide range of topics including application development, operating systems and technology in general. Anything is fair game if it plugs into the wall or takes a battery.</li>
<li><a href="http://elegantcode.com/" target="_blank">Elegant Code</a> - a blogging community of passionate software developers, architects, and technologists who share a feed.</li>
<li><a href="http://polymorphicpodcast.com/" target="_blank">Polymorphic Podcast</a> – podcasts by <a href="http://weblogs.asp.net/craigshoemaker">Craig Shoemaker</a>, a software developer, podcaster, blogger and New-Media Evangelist for <a href="http://infragistics.com/">Infragistics</a>. As host of the Polymorphic Podcast and <a href="http://getpixel8ed.com/">Pixel8</a>, Craig does what he loves most - making contributions to the community and drawing the best out of industry luminaries.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.sparklingclient.com/" target="_blank">Sparkling Client</a> – The Silverlight podcasts.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.sharepointpodshow.com/" target="_blank">Sharepoint Pod Show</a> -&nbsp; A Podcast All About SharePoint.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.dimecasts.net/" target="_blank">DimeCasts.NET</a> – inform and educate in ~10 minutes or less.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.summerofnhibernate.com/" target="_blank">Summer of NHibernate</a> - one-stop easy access to direct downloads of the screencasts related to NHibernate.</li>
</ul>
Hope you’ll find a lot of useful stuff on those sites.</div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>william</div>
<div class='content'>
Hi! Your blog is simply super. you have create a differentiate. Thanks for the sharing this website. it is very useful professional knowledge. Great idea you know about company background.<br />Increasing your web traffic and page views <A HREF="http://www.itsolusenz.com" REL="nofollow"><B>Add</B></A>, add your website in www.itsolusenz.com</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web 2.0 - Why Everything You've Been Taught Is Wrong]]></title>
    <link href="http://ApproachE.com/blog/web-20-why-everything-youve-been-taught/"/>
    <updated>2007-11-02T11:34:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://ApproachE.com/blog/web-20-why-everything-youve-been-taught</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
I had been watching some videos from <a href="http://developer.yahoo.com/yui/theater/">YUI Theater</a>. A lot of interesting stuff is there about client-side and front-end web development.

Must see videos are from <a href="http://video.yahoo.com/video/play?vid=111593">Douglas Crockford — "The JavaScript Programming Language"</a> (see all the 4 parts there).

But I really like one from from Joseph Smarr — <a href="http://video.yahoo.com/video/play?vid=1041101">High-performance JavaScript: Why Everything You've Been Taught Is Wrong</a>.
He gives overview of a real-world Web 2.0 web application (<a href="http://www.plaxo.com/">Plaxo</a>) and explains that many things that are in general a good practice (including patterns) are not always good. Just because of the performance.

Joseph says he met a guy who was so proud that he applied all of the patterns (that he knows?). But was there a need of it? Maybe yes, maybe not. But:

<span style="font-weight: bold;">Always think about performance, from the beginning to the end.</span>


See the video:
<embed flashvars="id=3881103&amp;emailUrl=http%3A%2F%2Fvideo.yahoo.com%2Futil%2Fmail%3Fei%3DUTF-8%26vid%3D1041101&amp;imUrl=http%253A%252F%252Fvideo.yahoo.com%252Fvideo%252Fplay%253Fei%253DUTF-8%2526vid%253D1041101&amp;imTitle=Joseph%2BSmarr%253A%2B%2526quot%253BHigh-performance%2BJavaScript%253A%2BWhy%2BEverything%2BYou%2526%252339%253Bve%2BBeen%2BTaught%2BIs%2BWrong%2526quot%253B&amp;searchUrl=http://video.yahoo.com/search/video?p=&amp;profileUrl=http://video.yahoo.com/video/profile?yid=&amp;creatorValue=ZXJpY21pcmFnbGlh&amp;vid=1041101" height="350" src="http://us.i1.yimg.com/cosmos.bcst.yahoo.com/player/media/swf/FLVVideoSolo.swf" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="425"></embed></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
